<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on Solar Bits</title>
    <link>https://thuri10.github.io/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on Solar Bits</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 15:53:55 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thuri10.github.io/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Android Application Security Part2</title>
      <link>https://thuri10.github.io/p/android-application-security-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 15:53:55 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thuri10.github.io/p/android-application-security-part2/</guid>
      <description>Insecure Storages This is the second part series of the android application security. This part focuses on the security of sqlite databases, firebase and AWS security.
Flag7 - Sqlite What is sqlite?
Sqlite is a structure query base database that enables applications to do local storage in the application directory. The goal of the challenge is to understand how local storage of databases may lead to leakage of information.
First step is to decompile the FlagSevenSqliteActivity using jadx.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Application Security Series- Part 1</title>
      <link>https://thuri10.github.io/p/android-application-security-series-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 20:19:29 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thuri10.github.io/p/android-application-security-series-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is a five part beginner series of Android application security with Vulnerable Android application examples. The application used in the first three part series is a vulnerable Android application developed by @B3nac.
The application is called InjuredAndroid, it covers different security concepts such as hardcoded secrets, weak cryptographic algorithms, misconfiguration, webview vulnerabilities etc. The application can be downloaded from the following provided links playstore or github.
For solving the challenges or following through the guides is you need to have an android phone or an emulator.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
